

CONTACT

ferenczhorvath@icloud.com linkedin.com/in/ferenc-horvath-bb3730 phone: +36 30 185 0468

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Business Development
Food & Beverage Management
Sales & Marketing
Financial Management
Hotel Opening
Business Analysis
Hotel Operations
Leadership & People Management
Revenue Management
Mergers & Acquisitions

EDUCATION

CORNELL UNIVERSITY
HOSPITALITY MANAGEMENT
2009
DIPLOMA, SALES AND MARKETING,
HUNGARY
2000
DIPLOMA, HOSPITALITY
MANAGEMENT & ADMINISTRATION,
USA
1999

ABOUT ME

A Hungarian award winning business strategist with two decades hospitality management experience. An expert in identifying and capitalizing on opportunities to build revenue; experienced in pre-openings, turnarounds and rapid growth in a highly competitive market. Able to recognize and respond quickly to changing market conditions and revise strategies accordingly. Bilingual professional who creates an environment that attracts and develops talent, fosters satisfaction with loyalty and encourages ownership with employee engagement workplace.

FERENC ZSOLT HORVÁTH

GENERAL MANAGER

WORK EXPERIENCE

VILNIUS GRAND RESORT, LITHUANIA

General Manager

2022 - present

• Hotel - Golf - Banquet - Spa & Wellness - Medical Centre

HOTEL EUROPA FIT , HUNGARY

Chief Executive Officer

2019 - 2022

- Managed 235 room of a thermal and wellness hotel & Medical Laser Centre.
- Awards: Accommodation of The Year 2020 & 2021, TripAdvisor Excellence 2021, Supporter of the Year by Red Cross 2022.

COURTYARD BY MARRIOTT AL BARSHA DUBAI, UNITED ARAB EMIRATES

Cluster General Manager

2017 - 2019

- Open and managed a business hotel of 240 room in Dubai.
- Supervised and directed the construction phase and opening of a second Marriott Courtyard Hotel in Dubai.

HOLIDAY INN AL QASR RIYADH, SAUDI ARABIA General Manager

2015 - 2017

- Ensured excellence and a unique visit for each guest at a 250+ room full service hotel with its 6000 m2 banquet space, through 300 employees.
- Awards: Franchise Front Runner Excellence, Employee Survey Excellence

COURTYARD MARRIOTT BUDAPEST CITY CENTER, HUNGARY General Manager

2010 - 2015

- Open and managed a 240 room hotel.
- Awards: Green Hotel of the Year, Gold Guest Satisfaction, Best Conference Hotel, Financial Excellence of the year

RENAISSANCE AKTAU HOTEL, KAZAKHSTAN General Manager

2008 - 2010

 Managed the Luxury Marriott property that held 120+ room with a large banquet capacity at the Caspian-Sea.

RENAISSANCE ATYRAU HOTEL and MARRIOTT EXECUTIVE APARTMENT ATYRAU, KAZAKHSTAN

Deputy General Manager

2008 - 2010

RAMADA HOTEL & RESORT LAKE BALATON, HUNGARY

General Manager

2006 - 2008

RAMADA HOTEL BUDAPEST, HUNGARY

Director of Operations

2004 - 2006

MARRIOTT BAYVIEW TABA HEIGHTS GOLF RESORT, EGYPT

Director of Food & Beverage

2002 - 2004

AMMAN MARRIOTT HOTEL, JORDAN

Director of Food & Beverage

2000 - 2002

KEMPINKI HOTELS - RADISSON HOTEL GROUP - CUNARD LINE Various Managerial Roles